{
  "reference_number": "11228",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Only if the target was to become more stringent"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - the third emissions budget should be able to be changed but only when the subsequent budget is set",
      "answer_index": 4,
      "notes": "Only if the target was to become more stringent"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "I think that the fiscal, economic, social, energy etc policies should be taking the Carbon Zero Target into account and should be\n\nadjusted accordingly rather than the other way around."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Makes decisions itself in respect of the number of units available in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 10,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "I fully support the ideas presented in the Zero Carbon Bill. I think that there needs to be a clear pathway not only for government but\nfor businesses, landowners and individuals on how they can reduce emissions and help sequester carbon. This could be through a\n\ncombination of education, incentives (eg reduction in insurance premium, govt payment) and deterrents (eg fines, increase in\ninsurance premium for not mitigating against climate change). There are many policies listed for reducing emissions as well as the\n\npolicy for planting 1billion trees to actually sequester the carbon. I think that there needs to be more done to sequester carbon. I\nbelieve that land owners/farmers hold a huge responsibility here as far as this goes. They are the guardians of our soils. Relatively\n\nsmall increases in soil organic matter amount to billions of tons of carbon stored. Any increase in soil organic matter and improvement\nin soil structure also greatly increases the rate of water infiltration and retention in soil. This helps minimize the frequency and severity\nof floods and droughts caused by land degradation. There should be education/policies for farmers on proper land management\n\npractices (eg never leaving bare soil (this can be done by planting crops into pasture), reduce amount of sprays, intensive grazing\nwith long rest times so that pasture can develop proper root systems etc). and should be rewarded as such for carbon that they\n\nsequester, as well as punishments for bad land management. I think farmers should be given help to carry out these things because\nit is such a vital role that they play. They can be part of the solution and not the problem. The benefits far out way the disadvantages:\n\nbetter water & pasture quality, less expenses, same carrying capacity etc. If you need any references regarding this information,\nplease let me know."
    }
  ]
}
